# John M. Farina

Phone: (404) 655 – 8823 Email: <u>John.farina0824@gmail.com</u> Clearance Level: TS/SCI with Full Scope Polygraph

## Summary

IT Security professional with a bachelor's degree in computer science from the University of North Georgia. Experience includes desktop, mobile, and web application development; signature development; network and target analysis; defensive and offensive cyber operations. Demonstrated leadership qualities by standing in as a team lead within a, high stakes, cyber environment. Extensive knowledge of networking fundamentals, defensive and offensive tools, and various programming languages.

## **Professional Experience**

### **Computer Network Defense Analyst**

## National Security Agency – June 2019 to Present

- Assess network and end-point behavior that threaten customer networks to detect and mitigate cyberspace threats
- Utilize C++ to aid in developing signatures used to sort through network traffic and identify malicious Cyber Actor activity.
- Utilize Python to develop solutions for analytical problems and tools to assist in the analytical process.
- Conduct analysis of metadata to identify network activity that posed a threat to customer networks.
- Execute triage processes to assess and prioritize leads against the given target set.
- Triage alerts to ensure countermeasures and tasking are completed efficiently.
- Report on adversary activities, behaviors, and tactics.
- Served eight months in an active Team Lead position; providing management to civilian, military, and contractor personnel.

### **Target Digital Network Analyst**

## National Security Agency – May 2018 to August 2018

Summer Intern Program for Information Assurance (SIP/IA) Participant

- Applied computer-based programs and various programming languages (Python and C++) to process data for analytical problems.
- Conducted Trend analysis against network/cyber activity by looking for networking patterns and protocols being used, in order to determine target traffic behavior patterns.
- Added, updated, or enriched information in mission-relevant databases.
- Conducted target analysis, target research, and analysis of metadata.
- Identified target communications within the global network.
- Selected, built, and developed query strategies against appropriate collection databases.

## **Data Analyst**

## Elringklinger USA – October 2017 to May 2018

- Organized and sorted through the down times of various machines while calculating a total monetary value lost during this time.
- Developed solutions to lower downtime rates, by identifying the variables that were affecting the rate of production and proposed possible solutions to upper management.

## **Engineering Specialist**

#### Elringklinger USA – May 2016 to September 2017

- Supervised Red Books (press setup/tooling instructions) to ensure updates and changes were made, when necessary.
- Used computer aided design software (AutoCAD and Solidworks) to produce revised layouts of portions of the production floor and designed numerous mechanical parts.
- Worked with upper management to begin the implementation of the 5S principles and the S.M.E.D. process throughout the plant.

## **Education**

B.S. Computer Science, Concentration in Information Assurance and Security

University of North Georgia, May 2019

### A.S. Computer Science

University of North Georgia, May 2017

## **Certifications**

CompTIA Security+, March 2020

## **Training**

Programming Languages: Python, Bash, Java, Dart, C++, C, C#, Swift, XML, HTML/CSS

Software Development Courses, University of North Georgia

- Software Engineering
- Data Structures & Analysis of Algorithms
- Mobile Application Development
- Artificial Intelligence

Information Security Courses, University of North Georgia

- Computer Forensics
- Network Security
- Computer Security
- Information Security
- Reverse Engineering
- Management of Information Security

External Vendor Training, EC-Council

- Certified Ethical Hacker
- Certified Network Defender

## **Additional Resources**

• GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/JFarina5">https://github.com/JFarina5</a>

• Portfolio: <a href="https://jfarina5.github.io/">https://jfarina5.github.io/</a>